# Valerio Lanziani

Curriculum Vitae

## Summary

Front end developer currently working on large scale web apps. Strong experience with React.js, Sass, Node and GraphQL. Great knowledge of JavaScript, Java and C++ programming languages. My career also comprises work with both non-relational and relational databases and the AWS Stack.

Strong willingness to constantly learn, improve, challenge myself and always glad to share my knowledge and skills with others.

## Experience

2018 - Now Front-end developer, ApplaudArt, Viterbo.

Currently working on the company's web platform using React.js, GraphQL and the AWS stack. My daily work includes design and implementation of modern web app features such as user's content creation (posts, comments and multimedia), geolocation and maps, chats and an e-commerce platform. The mainly used technologies are Redux, React Router, StripeJS, AWS Cognito, DynamoDB and AppSync.

2015 - 2018 Full stack developer, INTECS, Rome.

Worked as consultant on multiple projects focused on the management, analysis and processing of military data through a multi-tier architecture. In that time I helped designing and implementing user interfaces, business logic, microservices and APIs. Some of the utilized technologies were Qt framework, OracleDB, Spring framework, RabbitMQ, Apache Maven and Jenkins.

2014 - 2015 Back-end developer, TRANSLATED, Rome.

During my time in Translated, I was tasked on designing and implementing their first graph database, aiming on improving search results and overall performances. Other duties comprised the smart import and export of billions of records, development of the APIs and service layers and integration of the new features for the front end side. Main technologies were OrientDB, Neo4j, Redis, MySQL and Apache ActiveMQ.

#### Education

- 2015 **Master's Degree in Computer Engineering**, Roma Tre University, Rome.

  Graph-oriented extension on the Translation Memories' model in the translation industry
- 2012 **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering**, Roma Tre University, Rome. Visualization system of urban public transportation on maps

## Skills (sorted by experience)

OS Linux, Windows, OS X

Languages Javascript, Java, C++, PHP

Frameworks React, Node, Jest, Nextjs, AWS

Databases OrientDB, Neo4j, MySQL, Redis

Tools Git, Maven, Jenkins

### Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English Professional working proficiency